DAN KLEIN: OK, so today we're going to
talk about Adversarial Search, which
is how to decide how to act when there
is an adversary in your world.
So let's take a quick overview
of what the state of the
art is in game playing.
So here's one case, checkers.
In 1950, there was the first computer
player of checkers.
Kind of amazing, we actually saw this
earlier in the first lecture.
In 1950, there were already having
computers playing checkers.
They weren't actually that good.
In 1994, we had the first computer
champion, the computer program Chinook
ended the 40-year reign of the human
champion, Marion Tinsley.
Basically Marion Tinsley was
the world champion in
checkers for kind of forever.
No one else was anywhere near as
good, until there was Chinook
who dethroned him.
This was using the kinds of techniques
we're going to talk about today, plus
an exhaustive end game database
for kind of the last eight
pieces of the game.
In 2007, checkers was entirely solved.
And we'll talk today about
what that means.
So checkers--
you can't actually get any better
than solving the game.
So we're doing great.
How about chess?
The big event chess was in 1997
when Deep Blue defeated human
champion Gary Kasparov.
This was this amazing historic event
where Deep Blue was examining many,
many positions using custom hardware,
custom evaluation functions, and then
some methods that we don't entirely know
everything about that allowed it
to search much deeper into the tree.
And we'll see today why that's an
important thing to be able to do.
So in chess, how are we doing?
Well, I'd say we're better than
human experts at this point.
Have about Go?
So Go is a really hard
game for computers.
The reason why it's so hard is the
branching factor is immense.
It can be greater than 300.
So there was a very long time where even
though computers were dominating
at chess, and humans were afraid to play
them, humans were unwilling to
play them at Go, because it was kind
of insulting to the human.
Here's this computer, as far as you can
tell it's moving randomly and you
just crush it.
That's changed.
Very recently, there have been huge
advances in Go that use Monte Carlo
which basically means randomized methods
to expand much further into
the tree and be able to handle the fact
that in Go sometimes you need to
really, really look forward very far
to see the eventual consequence of
your action in a way that humans are
very good but brute force multiply
search is very bad at.
So in Go, the best humans are
still better, but we're
making amazing progress.
So the real question on all your
minds is what about Pac-Man?
Well, we don't really know, but we'll
see if we can make some progress on
that in this lecture.
So what's this all about?
Really, a general point in this course
is that what we'd like to be able to
do is take the definition of something--
a search problem, a game--
and be able to build a system which
exhibits intelligent behavior, where
that behavior comes not from hard coding
the behavior itself but from
some computation that's a general
purpose computation that can give rise
to very adaptive behavior that
does the right thing in
many possible scenarios.
So let's take a look at
an example of this.
We're going to see the
mystery Pac-Man.
So I'll run this in a second.
And what I want you to think while I run
this is what kinds of computations
must be happening inside this Pac-Man
playing agent in order to give rise to
the variety of behaviors that you see.
OK, so pretty good.
Question is how do we do
that kind of thing?
We'll talk about how to do
that kind of thing today.
And the important thing is we want to
at all costs avoid doing things like
programming "if you're within three
squares of a power pellet, eat the
power pellet.
If there is a scared ghost and the
scared ghost is within 10, then go
with the scared ghost."
Because things like that end up being
very fragile, and they'll do the wrong
thing when there's a scared ghost
and a power pellet and
two nonscared ghosts.
And we want some general
purpose computation.
And that's the topic for today.